{
	"question": "The rules concerning lights shall be complied with _____",
	"answer": "from sunset to sunrise",
	"options": [
			"from sunrise to sunset",
			"as long as the ship is underway",
			"if the ship is longer than 25 metres",
			"in restricted visibility only"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 20b",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "The rule concerning shapes shall be complied with _____",
	"answer": "by day",
	"options": [
			"at night",
			"at all times",
			"when the ship is underway",
			"when she is on anchor",
			"when she is aground",
			"when she is in distress"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 20d",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "What is the color of portside sidelight?",
	"answer": "red",
	"options": [
			"green",
			"white",
			"red or yellow light",
			"red or green light",
			"green or yellow light"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 21b",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "Flashing lights are lights flashing at regular intervals at a frequency of X flashes per minute. What is X?",
	"answer": "120 or more",
	"options": [
			"150 or more",
			"60 or more",
			"80 or more",
			"140 or more"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 21f",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "The sidelights if a vessel may be combined in one lantern carried on the fore-and-aft centreline of the vessel.",
	"answer": "this is true for vessels less than 20 metres in length",
	"options": [
			"this is true",
			"this is false",
			"this is false for vessels less than 20 metres in length",
			"this is true for vessels larger than 200 metres",
			"this is true for vessels smaller than 200 metres"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 21b",
	"chapter": 3
},//Day 4 - 8 new entry 5 of which are for the third chapter

{
	"question": "The masthead light shows an unbroken white light over an arc of the horizon of X degrees. What is X?",
	"answer": "225",
	"options": [
			"112.5",
			"135",
			"360",
			"120",
			"67"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 21a",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "The sidelights are either red or green lights showing an unbroken light over an arc of the horizon of X degrees. What is X?",
	"answer": "112.5",
	"options": [
			"225",
			"135",
			"360",
			"120",
			"67"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 21b",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "The masthead light is fixed to be seen from right ahead of X degrees abaft the beam on either side of the vessel. What is X?",
	"answer": "22.5",
	"options": [
			"12.5",
			"67.5",
			"13.5",
			"12.0",
			"42.5"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 21a",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "The sternlight is a white placed at/near the stern showing an unroken light over an arc of the horizon of X degrees. What is X?",
	"answer": "135",
	"options": [
			"225",
			"112.5",
			"360",
			"120",
			"67"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 21c",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "The sternlight is fixed to be seen X degrees from the right aft on each side of the vessel. What is X?",
	"answer": "67.5",
	"options": [
			"12.5",
			"22.5",
			"13.5",
			"12.0",
			"42.5"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 21c",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "Lights showing an unbroken light over an arc of the horizon of 360 degrees are referred to as?",
	"answer": "all-round lights",
	"options": [
			"round lights",
			"circular lights",
			"oval lights",
			"over-head lights"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 21e",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "What is the minimun visibility range of a white all-round light on towed objects or partly submerged vessels?",
	"answer": "3 miles",
	"options": [
			"3 kilometres",
			"6 miles",
			"6 kilometres",
			"2 miles",
			"2 kilometres"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 22d",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "You are on a vessel engaged in fishing is 25 metres in length. What would be the minimun visibility range of the towing light, the sternlight, the sidelight, the masthead light and the all-round light respectively?",
	"answer": "2, 2, 2, 5, 2 miles",
	"options": [
			"2, 2, 2, 3, 2 miles",
			"3, 3, 1, 5, 5 miles",
			"3, 3, 3, 6, 3 miles",
			"2, 2, 1, 2, 2 miles"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 22b",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "You find yourself on a tanker. The visiility range of masthead light, sidelights, sternlight, towing light and all-round light on the tanker are 7, 5, 3, 3, 6 miles respectively. If the vessel is abiding by the collision regulation, which of the following statements is true?",
	"answer": "the tanker is atleast 50 metres long",
	"options": [
			"the tanker is atleast 50 metres wide",
			"the tanker is atleast 15 years old",
			"the tanker is atmost 250 metres long",
			"the tanker is atleast 25 metres long"
		],
	"explanation": "write doen this question and compare to rule 22a to see the relationship",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "The visibility range of the masthead light, the sidelights, sternlight, towing light and all-round light of a Ro-Ro ship are 6, 1, 7, 8, 14 miles respectively. If the ship is abiding by the collision regulation, Which of the following statements is true?",
	"answer": "The ship is atleast 12 metres long",
	"options": [
			"The ship is atleast 120 metres long",
			"The ship is atleast 150 metres long",
			"The ship is atleast 50 metres long",
			"The ship is atleast 60 metres long"
		],
	"explanation": "study rule 22 deeply and you would find the answer. Hint: look at sidelights. It has the least visibility range.",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "Power driven vessels are obligated to exhibit 2 masthead lights, one port and starboard sidelights and one sternlight.",
	"answer": "this is true for vessels longer than 50 metres",
	"options": [
			"this is absolutely true",
			"this is absolutely false for vessels wider than 50 metres",
			"this is true for vessels less than 50 metres in length",
			"this is absolutely false"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 23a",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "What vessels are required to exhibit an all round flashing yellow lights?",
	"answer": "an air-cushion vessel operating in a non-displacement mode",
	"options": [
			"an air-cushion vessel",
			"a catamaran vessel",
			"a catamaran vessel operating in a non-displacement mode",
			"seaplanes when flying close to sea surface",
			"WIG crafts when landing"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 23b",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "A WIG craft when taking off, landing in flight near the surface shall exhibit a high intensity _____",
	"answer": "all-round flashing red light",
	"options": [
			"all-round flashing yellow light",
			"all-round red light",
			"flashing green light",
			"alternating flashing red and green light",
			"alternating flashing red and yellow light"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 23c",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "A power driven vessel of less than 7 metres in length whose X does not exceed Y may exhibit an all-round white light and shall, if practicable, also exhibit sidelights. What is X and Y?",
	"answer": "maximum speed, 7 knots",
	"options": [
			"minimun speed, 7 knots",
			"maximum length, 70 metres",
			"minimun length, 7 metres",
			"minimun gross tonnage, 140 GT"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 23d(ii)",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "The rule within the collision regulation that talks about 'Towing and Pushing' is _____?",
	"answer": "rule 24",
	"options": [
			"rule 23",
			"rule 22",
			"rule 25",
			"rule 28"
		],
	"explanation": "how about you check the options for this one?",
	"chapter": 3
}, //Another 15 questions entry made for chapter 3 :::TOTAL OF 20 CHAPTER 3 QUESTIONS IN THE SQL DATABASE AT THIS POINT

{
	"question": "You see a power-driven vessel of about 120 metres long exhibiting two masthead lights in a vertical line. Which of the following is true about the power-driven vessel?",
	"answer": "she is towing",
	"options": [
			"she is not under command",
			"she is restricted in her ability to manoeuvre",
			"she is constrained in her draught",
			"she is aground",
			"she is engaged in fishing"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 24a(1)",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "When the length of the tow exceeds 200 metres, a power-driven towing vessel shall exhibit _____",
	"answer": "a diamond shape where it can best be seen",
	"options": [
			"a diamond shape above the sternlight",
			"a diamond shape below the sternlight",
			"a triangle shape above the sternlight",
			"a circle shape below the sternlight"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 24a(5)",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "When a pushing vessel and a vessel being pushed ahead are rigidly connected in a composite unit, they shall be regarded as _____",
	"answer": "a power-driven vessel",
	"options": [
			"two power-driven vessels",
			"a power-driven vessel and a sailing vessel",
			"a vessel not under command",
			"two constrained vessels",
			"a power-driven vessel and a constrained vessel"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 24b",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "A sailing vessel less than 20 metres in length shall exhibit a sternlight, sidelights and may exhibit _____",
	"answer": "one lantern near the top of the mast",
	"options": [
			"two masthead lights where it can be seen",
			"three vertical masthead lights",
			"two horizontal masthead lights",
			"two lanterns at the top of the mast"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 25b",
	"chapter": 3
},{
	"question": "A vessel proceeding under sail when also being propelled by machinery shall exhibit forward where it can be best seen _____",
	"answer": "a conical shape, apex downwards",
	"options": [
			"a conical shape, apex upwards",
			"a pyrammid shape, apex downwards",
			"a triangle shape, apex upwards",
			"a pyrammid shape, apex downwards"
		],
	"explanation": "see rule 25e",
	"chapter": 3
},// for pard C i stopped at rule 26

{
	"question": "",
	"answer": "",
	"options": [
			""
		],
	"explanation": "",
	"chapter": 
},{
	"question": "",
	"answer": "",
	"options": [
			""
		],
	"explanation": "",
	"chapter": 
},{
	"question": "",
	"answer": "",
	"options": [
			""
		],
	"explanation": "",
	"chapter": 
},{
	"question": "",
	"answer": "",
	"options": [
			""
		],
	"explanation": "",
	"chapter": 
},{
	"question": "",
	"answer": "",
	"options": [
			""
		],
	"explanation": "",
	"chapter": 
},{
	"question": "",
	"answer": "",
	"options": [
			""
		],
	"explanation": "",
	"chapter": 
},{
	"question": "",
	"answer": "",
	"options": [
			""
		],
	"explanation": "",
	"chapter": 
},{
	"question": "",
	"answer": "",
	"options": [
			""
		],
	"explanation": "",
	"chapter": 
},{
	"question": "",
	"answer": "",
	"options": [
			""
		],
	"explanation": "",
	"chapter": 
},{
	"question": "",
	"answer": "",
	"options": [
			""
		],
	"explanation": "",
	"chapter": 
},{
	"question": "",
	"answer": "",
	"options": [
			""
		],
	"explanation": "",
	"chapter": 
},{
	"question": "",
	"answer": "",
	"options": [
			""
		],
	"explanation": "",
	"chapter": 
},{
	"question": "",
	"answer": "",
	"options": [
			""
		],
	"explanation": "",
	"chapter": 
},{
	"question": "",
	"answer": "",
	"options": [
			""
		],
	"explanation": "",
	"chapter": 
},{
	"question": "",
	"answer": "",
	"options": [
			""
		],
	"explanation": "",
	"chapter": 
},{
	"question": "",
	"answer": "",
	"options": [
			""
		],
	"explanation": "",
	"chapter": 
},{
	"question": "",
	"answer": "",
	"options": [
			""
		],
	"explanation": "",
	"chapter": 
},